Eric Yim

Junior Software Engineer Buford, GA | (404) 936-3858

Github | eric.tk.yim@gmail.com | Linkedin

Creative software engineer with the ability to pick up new languages and technologies as needed. Characterized by a passion for learning different things as I transitioned from studying and implementing the knowledge from kinesiology to now the world of software development. Having previously managed and worked within a team, I am able to cooperate and work with fellow programmers by taking in advice and feedback and sharing and bouncing off ideas to edify the quality of the project or product.

Software Development Skills

• Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, AWS, Express, Node.js, PostgreSQL, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, REST API

Education

DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA Georgia State University | B.S. Exercise Science | Atlanta, GA June 2020 – September 2020 August 2011 – December 2016

Software Development Portfolio

fourYou

A social media platform where users can share their interests with others. | Full-Stack

- **Primary role**: Team Lead; Front-End markup and styling, Javascript Function writer
- Worked in a remote setting while leading a team of four.
- Built with Javascript, Mustache pages, Bulma.io, PostgreSQL, Node.js, Express, Deployed through AWS

Goveri Prototype App

An app designed to support social and political activism. | Front-End

- **Primary role**: Front-End markup and styling, Javascript Function writer
- Worked in a remote setting in a team of three.
- Wrote javascript for the landing page and implemented Geo-Location/Zip Code API.
- Built with Javascript, HTML, CSS.

Dungeon Turn-Based RPG

A turn based RPG where you go through a maze and fight monsters.

- Created a text-scripted game in a remote setting.
- Built with Python.

Professional Work Experience

Sterling Estates of East Cobb | Interim Wellness Coordinator/Trainer | Marietta, GA February 2017 – January 2019

- Managed and maintained heated indoor-therapy pool, records and files of clients, and work-out equipment.
- Lead a group exercise which consisted of dynamic/static stretches, resistance bands, weighted equipment, and seated cardio.
- Trained clients one-on-one on land or water depending on their limitations and weaknesses such as gait, strength, and endurance.
- Worked along with Physical Therapists, Occupational Therapists, and Integrated Therapists for the same clients.

Georgia State University | Research - Vibration Therapy

Summer 2016 – Autumn 2016

Older Population (Age 65 and Older)

• A study to determine if vibration therapy can improve an older adult's balance

Dick Sporting Goods | Cashier, Ship-from-Store, Warehouse | Buford, GA

November 2014 – December 2015

- Exemplified courteous customer service
- Packaged and shipped items needed from online orders.
- Unload retail, hunting, and sports' equipment items from commercial trucks.